快回去
Turn back!
核心熔毁 三号反应堆
Mcltdown: Rcactor 3.
疏散人员
Evacuate personncl .
快啊 快啊 快啊
Come on, come on, comc on!
我们得走了  别慌 我能搞定
We gotta go!  Don't panic, I got this.
听着 你只用按下这里
Look, you just push hcre.
然后我们就完蛋了
And we're screwed.
快走
Come on.
快按啊
Push it!
卡住了
It's jammcd.
这是2022年的老核电站
It's an old 2022 plant.
有些模拟程序肯定能重新启动系统
Some analog program must rcboot thc system.
嘿 快看
Hcy look!
靠
Shit.
黄色还是蓝色
Ycllow or blue?
我的直觉说是蓝色
My instinct says blue.
为什么是蓝色  因为让人安心
Why bluc?  lt's reassuring.
才不呢 黄色才是 象征小鸡 太阳 生命
It isn't, ycllow is! It's chicks, the sun, l ife.
取决于你怎么看
Ucpends how you look at it.
不要按那个……
Uo not push thc...
怎么回事
What's that?
有个流浪汉凭空出现
This tramp appcared out of nowhcre.
他在告诉我们什么事
Hc's tclling us somcthing .
我听不见你说话 先生
I can't hcar you, sir.
那样会毁灭人类
...could destroy thc human race.
你离得太远了
You're too far away.
那我大声喊呢（I scream）
What if I scream?
冰淇淋（Ice cream）
Ice crcam?
叫他过来
Call him ovcr.
过来帮忙
Come hcl p out.
靠
Puck!
快 快 快
Run, run, run!
天啊 真是出师不利
Jcez, what a great starf!
现在能听见吗  好多了
Hear me now?  That's better!
我在说 不要按那个蓝色按钮
I was saying. . . Uon't push the blue button!
为什么
Why not?
你什么都没听到吗
You didn't hear a thing?
这个核电站会爆炸
The plant will blow up!
你确定吗
Are you surc?
对 我来自未来
Ycs! I'm from thc future.
他说啥
What did he say?
不要按蓝色按纽 我来自未来
"Don't push blue, I'm from thc future."
我们考考他 看他是不是在骗人
Lct's quiz him to sce if hc's tclling the truth.
我们没有时间
Wc don't have time.
好 我们信你  很好 我通常得解释半天
OK, we believe you.  Cool . I have a job usually.
那我们按黄色按钮
So wc push yellow?
看下说明书
Rcad the instructions.
这上面都是中文
It's all Chinese to us.
你们不是工程师吗
Aren't you cngincers?
是 但这些是中文
Ycs, but it's in Chincse!
给他看看
Show him.
我去去就回
I'll bc back.
他魔法般地消失了
Hc vanishcd as if by magic.
然后带了个人回来
And he's back with a guy.
这位是黄先生
This is Mr. Wong.
把卡片给他看
Show him thc card.
这是广东话 我讲的是普通话
他说啥
What's that?
对着这个说
Speak into this.
机器翻译
Machinc translation.
这是广东话 我讲的是普通话
That thing is in Cantonese. I spcak Mandarin.
我去去就回
I'll bc back.
我们要死了
Wc'rc going to die.
我们能相信他 他来自未来
Wc can trust him, hc's from the futurc.
还记得我吗
Rcmembcr me?
我一秒前才见过你
I saw you a second ago.
对你来说是一秒 而我花了六个月学了普通话
A second for you! I spcnt six months learning Mandarin.
广东话
Cantoncse.
我去去就回
I'll bc back.
对 我们要死了
Ycp, wc'rc going to die.
搞定  学会广东话了吗
Done!  Learnt Cantonese?
没 我回到过去 和核电站的设计师聊过了
I went into thc past and spoke to the plant's dcsigncr.
然后呢
And?
就是黄色按钮
It's the yellow button.
确定吗  快按
Sure?  Go on!
靠
Shit!
时间巡警 你被捕了
Time patrol . You're under arrcst!
快啊
Hurry up!
又来了两个人 那个流浪汉消失了
Two guys arc hcrc, the tramp's vanished .
我懵逼了
I'm lost.
黄色按钮
Ycllow button?
别按
No, don't!
蓝色按钮会把我们炸上天的
The blue will blow us sky high.
别管那个流浪汉 这是个圈套
Ignore thc tramp. It's a trap!
那个家伙是恐怖分子
The guy's a terrorist.
我们时间巡警是来帮忙的
The Time patrol is here to help!
你们原本打算干什么
What wcre you planning to do?
我们想…… 不对 是我想按下蓝色按钮
Wc wanted  well , I did  to push the blue button.
那就按 蓝色让人安心
Therc you go! Blue is rcassuring.
让人安心 我就是这么说的
Rcassuring! That's just what l said .
太好了
Great!
那我按了  先不要
So I push it?  Not yet!
为什么
Why?
等我们走了再按 好吗
Wait till wc'vc gonc, OK?
这很奇怪
That's weird.
这是协议
It's the protocol .
我们到底在等什么
What are we waiting for cxactly?
等我们发出明确的信号 先等着
A clcar signal from us. Just wait.
等着 好吗
Wait, OK?
好 按下蓝色按钮
OK, hit the blue button.
干得好 各位
Great, guys!
即将过载
Overload immincnt!
太棒了
Awesomc!
来自未来的访客
阿克索爆炸云
第五次穿越巴黎
阿克索的历史性核电站发生爆炸
受害者无数   谁是罪魁祸首
阿利伯特议员批准了阿克索核电站
好 我想我已经全部说到了 还有问题吗
Right, l think I've covered everything. Any qucstions?
谢谢你 阿利伯特先生
Thank you, Mr. Alibcrf.
这个核电站能惠及这个地区吗
Will the plant bcnefit the region?
它会带来显著的效益
It will havc significant bcnefits.
可以提供就业机会
It will providc cmployment.
要知道核能是最好的清洁能源
Rcmembcr that nuclear is the best clcan energy source.
所以如果全球变暖 那也不是我们的错
So if there's global warming, it won't be our fault!
先生
Sir?
你和阿克索是什么关系
What is your rclationship with Axamako?
我喜欢阿克索 他们能建造好的核电站
I l ike Axomako. They make good plants.
他们已在中国做出证明
They have provcd that in China
很快也会在这里证明的
and will soon do so hcre.
还有其他问题吗 不用害羞
Any more qucstions? Uon't be shy.
请提问
Go ahead .
阿利伯特先生
Mr. AIibert!
阿克索为何会在新的核电站使用过时的技术
Why docs Axomako usc obsolcte tcchnology in its ncw plants?
技术没有过时 而你也不是记者
The technology is not obsoletc, and you'rc not a journalist.
你是怎么进来的
How did you get in?
70年后 这项技术就有百年历史了
In 70 years' timc, the technology will bc 1 00 years old.
有巨大的风险 不是吗
It's a huge risk, isn't it?
我不赞同
I disagrec.
这没有风险
It's not a risk.
在未来一百年里 我们会找到解决方案
Over the next 1 00 ycars, wc'Il find solutions.
生活会很好
Life will bc good.
我们会背着喷气背包去面包店
And we'll go to the bakery by jctpack!
那太酷了
That'Il bc so cool !
阿利伯特先生
Mr. AIibert!
你关心地球吗
Uo you care about the planct?
小姐
Young lady,
我关心我的地区 我的地区就在地球上
I care about my region, and my region is on the planet...
所以我关心地球
so I care about my planet.
谢谢你们
Thank you.
祝大家下午愉快
Have a good afternoon.
拍我
Pil m mc.
别碰她
Uon't touch her!
坐下
Sit down!
拍到了没  再来一次
Did you gct that?  Do it again.
我说了别碰她
I said to Icavc her alonc!
再见
Goodbyc.
查理 住手
Charlic, stop!
快停下
Stop that!
我要撕烂你的脸
I'm gonna smash your facc in!
这混蛋在扯我头发
The bastard's pull ing my hair!
拍他
Pil m him!
干得好
Good job, guys!
也没有那么糟 卢西恩全都拍下来了
It wasn't that bad . Lucicn filmcd thc whole thing.
他们拿走了他的摄像机
They took his camera.
但我拿出了内存卡
Ycah, but I removed the SU card
塞进了我的屁股
and shoved it up my ass!
你真是天才  那是当然
You're a genius.  Sure am!
我不想上传这个 被捕不在计划之中
I don't want to post it. Gctting arrcstcd wasn't thc plan.
你不是认真的吧 大家都会谈论我们
You can't bc scrious! Everyone will talk about us.
我想要他们讨论这个核电站
I want thcm to tal k about the plant.
只发布信息
Only the message counts.
信息也需要个宣传的形象 不然没人会听我们的
A message nceds a facc. Otherwise wc won't be heard.
查理长得太丑  莫名其妙
Charlie's too ugly.  Gratuitous!
我要拍摄 所以我也不行 就只剩你了
I do the filming, so I can't. That Icavcs you.
有什么计划
What's thc plan?
最好就是你去坐牢
The best is for you to go to jail .
完美
Pcrfcct!
什么
What?
绝食抗议也很有效 那就绝食吧
Hungcr strikes are cffective too. Just go on hunger strike.
那你们做什么
What will you do?
发起标签运动 比如 释放爱丽丝
Launch a hashtag campaign. You know, #FrecAlicc
或拯救爱丽丝 我决定不了用哪个
or #SaveAlice. I can't dccide which.
我抽到了倒霉签是吧
I get the shorf straw, huh?
他屁股里塞着内存卡
Hc stuck an SD card up his ass.
还是64G的
B4GB it was too!
我拒绝做你们的发言人或殉道者什么的
I refuse to be your spokcsperson, marfyr or whatcvcr.
我会为事业而战 但我只是无名小卒
I'll fight for the cause, but I'm nobody.
真要命
What a pain.
你父亲来了
Your fathcr's here.
起来吧 我们走
Come on, let's go.
你喝多了  所以我有个司机
You drink too much.  That's why I have a drivcr.
要我送爱丽丝回家吗  去我的地方 法比奥
Shall I drop Alicc homc?  My placc, Pabio.
你可以睡你原来的房间
You can slecp in your old room .
你说了算
If you say so.
你的朋友很有趣
Interesting friends you have.
他们不是我的朋友
They'rc not my friends.
我在论坛上认识他们的
I met them on a forum.
网络
Internct!
别相信网上的东西
Uon't believe cvcrything you read .
饶了我吧
Give mc a break.
大家都知道阿克索修的是豆腐渣工程
Everybody knows Axomako builds shoddy plants.
他们会在你任期结束后雇用你
They'rc hiring you whcn your term's up.
这很经典 叫做
It's classic, it's called ...
走后门
A "rcvolting" door.
没错
That's it.
要不来点音乐吧
How about some music?
听着 爱丽丝
Look, Al ice,
我很担心你的未来
I'm concerncd about your future.
我过得很好  用的谁的钱
L'm doing fine.  With whosc moncy?
这个叛徒让我帮她付房租
The rebel Icts mc pay her rent!
你的网友会怎么说
What would your intcrnet pals say?
我喜欢这首歌 你听那个低音
I love this track. Listcn to that bass.
把那玩意关掉
Turn that crap off!
马上 先生
Right away, sir.
你挺棒 让自己受到了关注
Wcll done for getting yourself noticcd !
我不是为了博关注
I don't do it for that.
我知道 是为了地球
I know, I know, it's for the planet.
我不是白痴 我同样关心这些
I'm not an idiot. I care about these things too.
你妈妈就和你一样
Your mothcr was just likc you.
全身心投入
Totally committed.
她没有改变你
She didn't changc you!
她没有时间 你知道的
She didn't havc timc, as you know.
那是什么意思
What does that mcan?
没什么
Nothing.
继续说啊
Go on, say it.
说什么
Say what?
别再用妈妈做狡辩了
Stop the sly comments about Mom!
你总是这样
You do it all thc timc!
让我下车 法比奥
Urop mc hcrc, Fabio.
好的
All right.
靠
Shit.
回家 法比奥
Home, Fabio.
关掉音乐
And without music.
喂
Hcllo?
怪不得你有秘密信息
So that's why you had secrct info!
原来你是他女儿
You're his daughter.
不要告诉别人
Kcep it to yoursclvcs.
也不要把视频发上网 我谁也不是
And don't post the video. I'm nobody.
你是谁 爸爸的乖乖女吗
Who arc you? A l ittle daddy's girI
无聊了想找点乐子 这只是你的爱好吗
who's borcd and wants fun? It's just a hobby for you!
我想让他意识到他做的事是错的
I want him to real ize what hc's doing is wrong.
他意识到了吗  我想没有
And does he?  l gucss not.
听着 爱丽丝 要么百分百投入
Look, Al ice, either commit 1 00o/o
要么就老实待在家里
or stay in your bubblc!
我很投入 但我不知道要做什么
I am committed, but I don't know what to do.
我们得抓他现行
Wc havc to catch him out!
证明阿克索会在他任期结束后雇用他
Provc Axomako is hiring him when his term's up.
这会是个巨大的政治丑闻
It'Il be a mega political scandal !
很好 我该怎么做
Great! How do I do that?
你去偷他的电脑
You swipe his computer.
不行 没门
No way! I can't.
爱丽丝 别那么烦人 为别人着想一次
Alicc, don't bc a pain! Think of others for once.
我们做这些是为了地球
Wc'rc doing this for the planct!
如果你拒绝
If you refuse,
我们就上传视频 告诉大家他是你父亲
wc'Il post the video and tell cvcryonc hc's your dad.
把视频塞进你屁眼吧
Shovc the video up your ass!
我已经塞了 爱丽丝
I already have, Al ice.
行
Right.
好
OK.
生态还是死亡
嗨 亲爱的
Hi honcy!
真高兴来到你的工作室
How nice to be in your workshop!
让我们看看你在做什么
Show us what you're doing .
我快忙完了
I'm almost donc.
冰什么  这是我的最爱
Icc what?  lt's my favorite.
冰帽 最后的融化
"Ice Caps, the Pinal Meltdown! "
当心点防暴队 你还挺着大肚子
Watch out for thc riot squad , you and your bump.
他们不会攻击我们的
They won't chargc us!
那就好
Right, OK.
你在笑 看啊
You're laughing . Look.
你真美
You're so bcautiful .
我喜欢那个表情
I love that look.
我爱你  是吗
I love you.  You do?
当然啦
Of course I do!
我也爱你
Mc too.
你是谁
Who arc you?
你先说
You first!
我  对
Me?  Yes.
我谁都不是
I'm nobody.
好吧 真有闲心
OK. Grcat mood hcre!
行 听好了
Right, l istcn up.
这非常重要
This is vcry imporfant.
我叫……
My namc's...
怎么回事
What the hell's going on?
爱丽丝  爸爸
AIicc?  Dad .
那个流浪汉是谁
Who's that tramp?
不知道 我进来的时候他就在这儿
No idea. Hc was here whcn l came in.
他在找你的电脑
Hc was after your computcr.
你为什么在这儿
Why arc you here?
来跟我和好的吗
To makc up with me?
没错
That's right.
抱歉 我以为你也是来偷我电脑的
Sorry, l thought you'd comc to steal my computer too.
你疯了吗  被我亲生女儿抢劫
Arc you nuts?  Robbcd by my own daughter!
那你是吗
Wcll , did you?
是
Ycs.
但我打昏了他
But I knockcd him out.
是你的同谋吗  我不认识他
Your accomplicc?  l don't know the guy.
我要报警  好主意
L'm calling thc police.  Good idca.
等等 你打算怎么说
Wait! What are you going to say?
时间巡警  不要太惊讶
Time patrol .  Don't bc surprised!
那是什么啊
What the hell's that?
他们在哪儿
Wherc are they?
我没看到他们  方向反了 维克多
I can't sce thcm!  Wrong way, Victor.
他们在这儿
Therc they are.
我来解决他  他没有武器
L've got him.  He isn't armcd.
那又怎样
So what?
好 听我说
Right, l istcn to me.
我来自未来
I'm from thc future.
如果吉尔伯特建了核电站 就会发生这件事
If Gilberf builds his plant, hcre's what's gonna happcn.
我要干掉他  别
I'm taking him out.
靠
Puck!
你个蠢货
You idiot!
他是我的
Hc's mine.
爸爸
Uad !
好吧 如果他躲一下……
Ycah, well if he moves...
靠 好痛
Puck, it hurfs!
你放开我
Gct off mc, you!
别碰我爸爸
Uon't touch my dad .
他要去抓目标
Hc's taking thc target!
快点
Hurry!
不许动
Preeze!
该死的
Goddamn it!
老大要大发雷霆了
The boss will be super pissed off.
我要出卖你们
I'm ratting you guys out.
来喝点
Urink o'clock!
爸爸  没事吧 爱丽丝
Dad!  AIl right, Alice?
放开我
Gct off mc!
别碰我
Lcavc me alone!
放开我
Gct off mc!
为什么带他来这儿 她是谁
Why bring him here? Who's that?
谁都不是
Nobody.
处理她 我来处理她爸爸
Ucal with hcr, I'll dcal with the dad.
你好
Hcy thcre!
不用担心
Therc's no need to worry.
回来  快跑 爱丽丝
Come back!  Run, AIicc.
快跑
Run!
这是怎么回事
What is this?
滑门打开
Trapdoor Room opcning.
什么情况
What's that?
进展如何
How did it go?
路易丝失手了 她没打中目标
Louise messcd up. She missed her targct.
我没失手
I did not.
我打中一个
I got one.
打中大腿  好样的
I n the leg.  Attaboy!
不幸的是中枪的人是我们应该保护的人
Unfortunately it was the guy wc wcrc supposcd to protcct.
他们逃走了
They got away.
他们很聪明
They'rc so smart.
不 他们没有 他们没我们那么差劲
No, thcy're not! They'rc Icss Iamc than us.
没你差劲
Than you.
她在气自己失了手  一向如此
Shc's mad shc messed up.  Typical !
我没有失手
I did not mcss up.
我们去听听老大怎么说
Lct's see what the boss says.
她生气吗
Is she pisscd off?
我不生气
I'm not pissed off.
我只是不解
I'm confused.
简而言之
In a nutshell ,
路易丝试图击毙捣乱者
Louise tried to shoot thc troublemakcr
但马提欧阻止了她
but Matteo stoppcd her.
然后维克多朝他们开枪
Then Victor shot at them.
他打偏击中了吉尔伯特·阿利伯特
Hc missed and hit Gilberf Al iberf, who was kidnapped
他随后被绑架到了2555年
around thc year 2555.
谢谢你 理查德
Thank you, Richard .
我想指出主要责任在于马提欧
I would Iikc to point out it was mainly Matteo's fault.
谢谢你 理查德
Thank you, Richard .
维克多不该参与这次任务
Victor should not havc bcen on the mission.
他对自己和他人都是个威胁
Hc's a dangcr to himsclf and others.
再次感谢
Thanks again.
马提欧 你对自己的举动作何解释
Mattco, how do you cxplain your actions?
我们的任务不是当场击毙嫌疑犯
Our mission is not to shoot suspects on sight.
他是我们巡逻队对付过的最坏的罪犯
Hc is the worst criminal our patrol has ever dcalt with.
逮捕他和他的同伙是我们的首要任务
Hc and his accompl ices are our priority.
看到了吗 康斯坦斯 我把他投在大屏幕上了
Sce that, Constance? I put his face on the big scrcen.
这个疯子认为自己在拯救世界
The madman thinks hc's saving thc world!
他可以破坏时空连续体
Hc could destroy the spacetime continuum.
你知道这意味着什么吗
You know what that means?
当然 我知道这些东西
Course l do. I know all that stuff.
路易丝将取代你担任队长
Louise is rcplacing you as mission leader.
抱歉
Sorry?
太好了 我是说 遵命
Awesomc. I mean, affirmative.
马提欧 你不能在通报会中离开
Mattco, you can't Icave a bricfing!
随他去 理查德
Lct him go, Richard.
我也能离开吗
Can I leave too?
路易丝
Louise,
我要你找到吉尔伯特·阿利伯特
I want you to find Gilbert AIibcrf
并消灭潜在的敌人
and climinate potential cncmics.
太艰巨了 我是说 没问题
Tough job. I mean, you bet!
我是说 遵命
I mean, affirmative.
别让我后悔自己的决定
Uon't makc me regret my decision.
康斯坦斯
Constance,
还有一件事
therc's somcthing elsc.
吉尔伯特不是唯一一个被绑架的
Gilbcrf Aliberf wasn't thc only one kidnapped.
爱丽丝 你醒了吗
Alicc, arc you awakc?
爸爸
Uad?
你在哪里  这儿
Whcrc are you?  Here!
你没事吧
You OK?
我们在哪儿  我不知道
Whcrc are we?  l don't know.
外面很荒凉 可能在比利时
It's dcsolate out there. Bclgium maybe?
不是比利时 是巴黎
It isn't Belgium, it's paris.
只是有所不同
Only diffcrcnt.
我们得离开这里
Wc havc to get out of here!
他们是恐怖分子 去和他们谈判
They'rc tcrrorists. Ncgotiate with them.
为什么是我去
Why me?
因为你和嬉皮士是一类人
Bccausc hippies are your dcpartment.
你的腿没事吧
Is your Icg OK?
没事
Ycs, fine.
他们想处理伤口 不过手法粗糙
They tried to patch it up. It's a botch job.
他们的手很脏 我想我肯定会得破伤风
Their hands were filthy. I bet I havc tctanus.
有人来了  揍扁他们
Someone's coming.  Beat thcm up!
你说得轻巧
That's easy for you to say.
你好 顺便说一句 我们什么都能听到
Hcy thcre. Wc can hear evcrything by the way.
我给你准备了这个
I fixed you this.
请慢用
Enjoy!
这是食物吗
That's food?
天生爱抱怨
Born complainer, huh?
这当然是食物 是这里最好的了
Of course it's food. The best you can get herc.
走出你21世纪的潮人舒适区吧
Move outsidc your 21 stccntury hipster comforf zonc.
这里是未来
This is the future.
你可以忘掉你的早午餐
You can forget your brunchcs.
现在早午餐就是这个
This is brunch now.
那是怎么回事
What was that?
我们在哪里
Wherc are wc?
在未来
In the future.
你在说什么
What are you on about?
外面一片狼藉
It's awful outside.
所以我们才不出去
That's why we don't go.
不过别担心 我带了我的游戏机
But don't worry, I brought my consolcs with me.
想不想玩《FIFA》
Want to play PI PA?
好主意
It's a nice idca
但我不打算在这个监狱呆太久
but I don't plan to stay Iong in this prison.
你得带我们回家
You have to take us home.
再说吧 还有这里不是监狱
Wc'Il see. Only this isn't a prison,
这是我的卧室
it's my bcdroom .
你住在这儿  对
You livc herc?  Yeah.
我以前和你一样 我来自“现在”
I uscd to bc Iikc you. I came from thc "prcscnt"
然后我遇到了这个人
then I met this guy.
我穿梭时空 永远改变了我的生活
I travcled in time and it changed my Iifc forcver.
你之前是做什么的
What did you do beforc?
我只会打游戏
I just playcd video games.
那现在呢
And now?
如果这里不是监狱
So if this isn't a prison,
我们能离开吗
can we leavc?
去问其他人 我做不了主
Ask thc othcrs. I don't gct to dccide.
我排行老三
I'm number thrce in the hicrarchy.
一共有三个
Out of threc.
你可以去实验室里商量
You can discuss it in thc lab.
走吧
Come on.
我也想出去
I want out too!
你好 爱丽丝
Hcllo, AIicc.
还记得我吗 你想揍扁我
Rcmembcr me? You tried to bcat mc up.
好几次了
Scveral timcs.
你有名字吗  当然
Do you have a namc?  Sure.
但我一直没机会告诉你
But I didn't gct thc chancc to tell you.
好 我叫……
OK, so my name...
人们会找我们的
pcople arc looking for us.
我劝你放了我们
I advise you to let us go!
你想离开了吗
You want to leavc alrcady?
门就在那儿
The door's there.
真的吗
Rcally?
好
Right.
爱丽丝 跟着我
Alicc, follow me.
不好意思
Excuse me.
按钮在边上
The button on thc sidc.
我想也是
I thought so.
多谢
Thanks!
有人告诉过你们吗
Uidn't anyone tell you?
未来到处都是丧尸
The futurc is full of zombies.
为什么
Why?
问得好
Excellcnt question!
你好 我是亨利·卡斯塔福特博士
Hcllo, l'm Dr. Hcnry Castafolte.
这些行尸走肉 俗称丧尸
How did the undead , commonly known as zombies,
是如何出现在地球的呢
appear on our planet?
首先 我们必须将他们与感染者区分开来
Pirst we must distinguish them from the infected,
后者通常被称为奔跑丧尸
vcry commonly known as running zombics.
为什么叫奔跑丧尸
Why running zombies?
因为他们会跑  没错
Because they run.  Corrcct!
你看到的丧尸都是活死人
The zombics you saw are undead .
他们是行尸
They are walking zombies.
因为他们只能行走  我问你了吗 拉夫
Because they wal k.  Did I ask you, Raph?
你打断我了
You interrupted me.
真是无礼 把饼干放下
How rude! put that biscuit down.
去吧
Uo it.
他们为什么成为丧尸
Why arc they zombies?
辐射
Radiation.
就这些吗
Is that all?
真正的问题是 为什么会有辐射 吉尔伯特
The real qucstion is, why thc radiation, Gilbert?
我没说错
I was right.
你的核电站会爆炸 爸爸
Your plant will cxplode, Uad .
不是我的 是阿克索的
It isn't mine, it's Axomako's.
不能把所有灾难都怪在我头上
I'm not to blame for all the disasters!
他说的没错
Hc's right.
许多核灾难是由地震引起的
Many nuclcar disastcrs wcre causcd by earfhquakcs.
还有《猫狗大战》
And thc Cat War.
什么
The what?
我没有造成辐射
I didn't cause all thc radiation.
在我们那个世界
Wherc we're from,
核能的危害更小
nuclcar is the Icsscr evil .
你宁愿我建个煤电厂吗
You'd rather I built a coal plant?
这不是问题所在
That isn't the problem.
我只是想在竞争激烈的市场中
I simply tried to optimize thc budget
优化预算
in a highly compctitive market.
所有安全标准都已符合
All safety standards werc met.
如果它没有翻新 不能怪我
I'm not to blame if it wasn't rcnovated.
从来都不是你的错 这就是问题所在
It's ncver your fault. That's thc problcm!
你把所有风险留给后代
You bequeath your risky ventures to future gcnerations
还希望我们神奇地解决问题
and hope we'll magically fix things!
剧透一下 我们没有超能力
Spoiler alerf: Wc havc no powcrs.
我们甚至连厕所都没有 只能在桶里拉屎
Wc don't cvcn have toilets, wc crap in buckets!
这就是未来
That's thc futurc.
未来
The futurc?
我们怎么知道这是未来
How we do know this is the future?
你的喷气背包呢
Wherc are your jctpacks?
你们要去哪里
What are you up to?
我们要出去
Wc'rc going out.
等等 那些丧尸怎么办
Hang on, what about the zombics?
什么丧尸
What zombies?
等等
Wait!
他真是奇丑无比
Hc's super ugly.
那就是我 妈妈  的确如此
That's me, Mom.  So it is!
那是什么  我们在哪儿
What's that?  Whcrc are we?
离我们更近了
It's come even closcr.
下车
Gct out.
吉尔伯特 我们简单说下
Gilbcrf, we'll kcep it simple.
如果你建了核电站 这就是会发生的事
If you build your plant, hcre's what's gonna happcn!
那是什么
What's that?
这就是你在竞争激烈的市场中
It's what happcns when you optimizc your budget
优化预算的后果
in a compctitive markct.
这片爆炸云飘过了大西洋
The blast cloud driftcd across thc Atlantic.
所有人都认为这是美国的问题
Everybody figured it'd bc America's problem .
他们忘了一些事
They'd forgottcn something.
什么事
What?
地球是圆的
The Earfh is round .
太蠢了
That's dumb.
每隔70年 爆炸云就会绕地球一圈
Every 70 years the cloud circles the globc
杀死百分之五十的人口
and kills 50O/o of thc population.
每次都变得更大
It's biggcr evcry timc.
真的很大  那是当然
It's really big.  lt sure is.
这次无人能幸免
No one will survive this time.
你现在明白问题了吗 吉尔伯特
Uo you understand the problcm now, Gilbcrf?
是 非常清楚
Ycs, it's pcrfcctly clear.
很好 正合我意
Great! That suits mc.
住手 你疯了吗
Stop! Are you insanc?
他说他明白了  对
He said hc undcrstood .  Right.
别杀他
Uon't kill him!
这是为了拯救人类
It's to savc the human racc.
难道没有别的办法吗
Isn't there another solution?
有啊
Therc was!
我想偷他的电脑 制造一个丑闻
I tried to steal his computer, to create a scandal .
但有人阻止了我
But someone stopped mc.
我当时不知道 这也是我的主意
I wasn't to know. It was my idea too!
我感觉不舒服
I don't fcel good.
在你的现在 时间巡警会找到你
In your present, the Time patrol will find you
让你顺应时间发展
and kecp you on the Tracks of Time.
对不起 吉尔伯特
Sorry, Gilbcrf.
别 别 爸爸
Uon't, don't. . . Dad?
爸爸
Uad !
爸爸 快醒醒
Uad , wake up.
我不能杀一个昏迷的人  这样会不讲武德
I can't kill an unconscious man.  Hardly sporfing.
我有个想法
I've got an idca.
大人在说话
The adults are tal king!
为了不让时间巡警注意到时间变化
Por thc Timc patrol not to notice a timc changc,
那就必须是内部改变
it has to bc an intcrnal change.
虽然很惊讶 但是他说的对
It's astonishing but he's right.
如果一个人发生心理变化
If an individual undergocs psychological changc,
如果他们顿悟了
if they expcricnce an epiphany,
他们可以改变时间进程
they can changc the course of Time
巡警也阻止不了他们
and thc patrol can't stop them .
求你们了
Please.
我肯定他会改变
I'm sure he can changc.
我不肯定 反正也没有时间了
I'm not. Therc's no timc anyway.
他并非一直如此
Hc wasn't always l ike this.
如果巡警找到我们 就别怪我狠心
If the patrol finds us, I'll take action.
明白了吗  明白
Is that clear?  l understand.
我不是很确定
I'm not so surc.
我们回去
Lct's get back.
爸爸 没事了
Uad ! It's OK...
我帮你
Lct me help you.
谢谢 拉夫
Thanks, Raph.
不客气
No, well , er...
我们会一起做这件事
Wc'Il do thc thing.
什么
What?
我是说 我觉得我们能改变你爸爸
What I mean is, I think wc can change your dad .
前提是时间巡警没有抓到我们
If the Time patrol doesn't catch us first.
嘿 你
Hcy, you!
现在是见人就开枪吗
So. . . it's shootonsight now?
我们没时间搞外交 康斯坦斯指望着我们
Wc'vc no time for diplomacy. Constance is counting on us.
马屁精
Ass licker!
你们是谁  时间巡警
Who are you?  Thc Timc patrol .
你认识他们吗
Uo you know thcm?
认识 但为什么开枪打我
Ycs, I do. But why shoot me?
你问一下不就行了
You simply had to ask.
抱歉 你知道他们在哪儿吗
Sorry. Uo you know whcrc they are?
知道 但我现在不会告诉你
Ycs, but I'm not telling you now.
你弄伤了我
You've upset mc.
干得好 路易丝
Good job, Louise!
听着 告诉我们他们在哪儿 然后我们会照顾你
Look, tell us whcre they are then wc'Il tend to you.
不
No.
先照顾我
Treat me first.
如果他不说 我们就打他另一条腿
If hc refuscs to tell us, wc shoot his othcr leg.
他们的实验室在东区 那边走 往左
Their lab is in the East Maze. That way, Icft,
有个狐狸图案的坚固房门就是
strong door with a fox on it.
去吧
Therc you go!
你们只需问一下
You simply had to ask.
我们走吧
Therc we go!
理查德说我很危险 但是……
Richard says I'm dangcrous but...
东区是吧 他说东区
East Maze? Hc said the East Maze.
所以一定是在东边
So it has to bc cast.
走这边
Right, this way.
看来今天会很漫长
It's gonna be a long day.
谁要喝一杯 爱丽丝
Who's up for a drink?
来一杯吗
A cold onc?
认真的吗
Scriously?
我们是朋友还是人质
Are we buddies or hostagcs?
你差点杀了我爸爸
You almost shot my dad.
拯救世界没那么简单
Saving thc world isn't that simple.
我知道
Ycah, I know.
我们在同一条战线上
Wc'rc fighting the same fight.
只是方法不同
With diffcrcnt mcthods!
没错 你是业余的 我们是专业的
That's right. You're an amatcur, we're pros.
如果是专业的 那就付我工钱
If wc're pros, pay me.
已经付过你了 拉夫
You arc paid, Raph.
钱在哪儿
Wherc's the money?
用来付你的房租了
It pays for your room.
你觉得我会免费让你住吗
Think I'd put you up for free?
爱丽丝 我的意思是
What I mean is, Al ice,
我们不会真的杀人 从来没有
wc don't really kill peoplc. Wc ncvcr have.
就算杀过 也不是为了好玩
Or if we have, it wasn't for plcasurc.
杀丧尸算吗 我杀丧尸觉得很好玩
Uo zombies count? I get a kick out of killing them.
丧尸不算
Zombies don't count.
不要那么害怕丧尸
Uon't be so zombiephobic.
饶了我们吧
Give us a break!
有什么计划  现在吗
What's thc plan?  Right now?
去喝一杯 我们的酒吧调的酒很棒
To havc a drink. Our bar does great gnat's pee!
认真点
Scriously.
对于我爸爸
Por my dad .
有什么主意
Any idcas?
不对吧 爱丽丝 你说你有个主意的
Crossed wircs, Alicc. You said you had an idea.
不 我没说过
No, I did not.
我说他可以改变
I said he could changc.
妈妈还在世的时候
When Mom was still around ,
她可以改变他的想法
she could change his mind .
他是这样说的
Or so he says.
我从不认识她
I never knew hcr.
为什么
Why?
你妈妈是不是……
Uid your mom. . .?
分娩死亡
In Iabor.
阿利伯特先生
Mr. AIibert?
你的孩子没事
Your child is fine.
但是出现了并发症
But thcre wcre complications.
你的妻子大出血
Your wife hcmorrhagcd.
她去世了
She dicd .
我想他肯定希望医生救的是妈妈
I bet he wished they'd saved Mom instcad.
我们可以……
Wc could ...
我们不会复活你妈妈的
Wc'rc not bringing your mom back to l ife.
为什么不
Why not?
太冒险了
It's too risky.
If wc savc your mom and cancel the baby you,
如果我们救了你妈妈 阻止你的出生
it'Il creatc a paradox.
就会产生悖论
What?  A paradoxical thing! Porget it.
什么  就是自相矛盾 算了吧
Thanks a lot!
多谢你啊  他是说
What he mcans is,
你会不存在般地存在
you'd cxist without existing.
你会是一个异常
You would bc an aberration.
别担心 爱丽丝 我也不懂这些时间的玩意
Uon't worry, Alice, I don't gct this time stuff either.
你爸爸没意识到谁会是他行为的受害者
Your dad docsn't realize who thc victims of his acts will bc.
首先是我们
Therc's us for starfers.
他不会在乎你
Hc doesn't carc about you.
他必须看到真实的人
Hc has to sce real peoplc.
遭难的平民 儿童
Civilians in distress, childrcn...
那样会很好  我们去老巢吧
That'd be grcat!  Let's go the Lair.
拉夫 闭嘴
Raph, shut it!
什么老巢
What's thc Lair?
没什么
Nothing.
我有个更好的主意
I have a better idea.
太赞了
Uamn, that's good!
做得好
Good job!
很好
Great.
嘿 别出老千  冷静
Hey, don't cheat!  Chill .
要点什么
What'Il it be?
你们有些什么威士忌  我们要白水
What whisky do you havc?  We'Il havc watcr.
白水 自来水吗
Water? Tap watcr?
你是新凡尔赛女王吗
Are you the Oucen of Neo Vcrsailles?
卧槽
Pucking hcll !
别说了 弗朗西斯 给他们来一样的
Urop it, Francis. They'Il havc the same.
给女王
Por thc Ouecn!
你是做什么的
What do you do?
我搞大批交易的
I tradc in bulk.
商人啊 你是卖什么的
Ah, a trader! What do you sell?
我刚说了 卖批
I just told you: bulk!
你有家人吗
Uo you have family?
有的 有迪迪埃
Ycs. Therc's Didier,
我父亲 我哥哥 我叔叔
my father, my brothcr, my uncle...
我猜猜看 他们是同一个人
Lct me gucss, hc's one and the same.
对
Ycp.
你有孩子吗  没有
Uo you have kids?
要我的吗 便宜卖了
Want mine? They'rc going chcap.
鲍里斯 你答应把他们给我的
Boris, you promised them to mc!
你吃了我给你的最后一个
You atc the last onc I gavc you.
是 但我付了钱的
Ycs, but I paid for it!
我们走吧
Come on, let's go.
亨利说他在工作 不过我觉得……
Hcnry says he's working, but I think...
他在打飞机  肯定的
he's jerking off.  Por surc.
让他们自己呆着安全吗
Is it safc to leave them alonc?
没事的 拉夫 我一直看着他们
It's OK, Raph, I'm kecping an eye on thcm.
买一送一  不用 谢谢
Two for one!  No thank you.
最坏的情况 吉尔伯特会死
At the very worst, Gilbert will dic.
是 不过爱丽丝是无辜的
Ycs, but AIice is innocent.
我倒不担心她 她学得很快
I'm not worried about her. She's a fast Icarner.
我在考虑雇佣她
I'm thinking of hiring hcr.
她不会同意的
She'll never agrce.
她热衷于拯救世界
She's into saving the world.
也许她想成为专业的
Maybc she'd l ike to go pro.
我没想到他们会如此古怪
I didn't think they'd be so wcird .
别担心 你的计划很聪明
Uon't worry, your plan is vcry smarf.
是吗 谢谢
It is? Thanks.
争取时间让时间巡警找到我们
Buying time so the Time patrol finds us!
计划并非如此
That isn't the plan.
我希望你能改变
I want you to changc.
拜托 爱丽丝 人到四十不会变
Come on, AIice, no one changes at 40!
脸书上是这么说的
It says so on Facebook.
但是爆炸云会杀死他们
But thc cloud will kill thcm all .
真可怕啊 雷吉斯再也不能吃鲍里斯的孩子了
How awful ! Rógis won't get to cat Boris's kids.
还会有其他受害者啊
Therc'll be other victims too.
我不在乎他们 我只在乎你
I don't givc a damn about them! I only care about you.
我
Mc?
你甚至都不了解我
You don't even know mc.
但我是你父亲
But I'm your father!
好 我最爱的系列是什么
OK. What's my favoritc scries?
哦 这太简单了 是……
Oh, come on, that's easy. It's...
《小乌龟富兰克林》
Pranklin thc Turfle.
那是我五岁时 爸爸
When I was 5, Dad!
你沉醉在你的事业里
You're obsessed with your carcer!
我知道我整天都在忙工作
I know l've becn working 24I7.
但作为父亲 我必须保证我们的未来
But as a father, I have to sccure our futurc.
如果你在乎未来 我们就不会在这儿了
If you cared about thc future, wc wouldn't be hcre!
我能说什么
What can I say?
政党结束 我也完蛋
The parfy's screwed and I'm donc for.
阿克索打算雇用我 我们可以腰缠万贯
Axomako plans to hire me. Wc'Il be roll ing in it.
你会的  是谁资助你
You will be!  Who funds you?
我能自己养自己  是啊
I can fcnd for myself.  Sure!
你连一份工作都保不住
You can't even hold down a job.
如果你是叛徒 那就付房租
Pay your rent if you're a rebcl .
或者加入你未来的狐朋狗友
Or join your pals from the future!
我想 但我不能 那片云会杀死他们
I'd like to, but l can't. The cloud's going to kill them .
她说什么
What did shc say?
安静点  怂了吗
Be quiet.  Lost your nervc?
他们不必知道
They don't need to know.
大家听好了
Listcn up, guys!
我有些可怕的消息
I've got some terriblc ncws.
你们快要死了  什么
You're all going to dic.  What?
被巨大的毒云闷死
Smothered by a huge toxic cloud.
他就是罪魁祸首 他叫吉尔伯特
Hc's to blame. His name's Gilberf.
打倒吉尔伯特
Uown with Gilbcrf!
听我说
Listcn to mc.
冷静点 朋友们
Cal m down, my friends.
我请大家喝酒
The drinks are on mc!
你想多了 我们走
Nice try. Lct's go!
他们跑了
They'rc gctting away!
谁买单
Who's paying?
现在去哪儿  谁在乎 巡警会找到我们的
Whcrc to now?  Who carcs! The patrol will find us.
记在我账上
Put it on my tab.
别当我是傻瓜
Uon't takc me for an idiot!
我在努力工作
I'm hard at work.
我很忙
I'm busy...
我想看无毛宝贝
I want to sce hairlcss babcs!
维克多
Victor.
炸药
The cxplosives.
1 0,
9...
5,
4...
我能听见数字
I can hear numbers.
在倒数
Only backwards.
趴下
Gct down!
快啊
Come on!
太热 就吃冰淇淋
It's hot, hotta chocolatta!
你们没事吧
You OK, guys?
没事
Ycah, finc.
维克多
Victor?
倒计时
A countdown.
那些数字是倒计时
That's what thosc numbers werc.
快
Come on!
用力推
Push hardcr!
来吧
Come on.
地面不是最安全的地方
The surface isn't the safest place.
要是有喷气背包就好了 未来也太拉跨了
If only wc had jctpacks. The futurc's such a Ictdown.
为什么对喷气背包如此着迷
Why thc obscssion with jctpacks?
为什么不着迷
Why thc nonobsession?
每个人都想要一个去面包店
Everyone wants one to go to the bakery!
没有喷气背包的未来不值得拯救
A future without jetpacks isn't worfh saving.
我们走
Lct's go.
这一点都不吓人
This isn't at all scary!
你们好  卧槽
Hello.  Puck!
这是干嘛
What's that?
你怎么一个人
Why arc you alonc?
我不是一个人 还有你们在
I'm not alone, you're here.
你叫什么名字
What's your name?
我叫玛沃丝 你们是福克斯的朋友吗
I'm Mouse. Are you Pox's friends?
谁
Who?
韦斯说不要和任何人讲话
Wcascl said not to talk to anyone
除了福克斯的朋友
except Pox's fricnds.
韦斯和福克斯是谁
Who arc Wcasel and Fox?
韦斯照顾我们 她和福克斯是情侣
Wcascl looks aftcr us. She and Pox arc swecthearts.
他们没有公开 不过我看见他们接吻了
They don't show it, but I've secn thcm kissing.
再见 丧尸来了
Sce you! The zombics arc coming.
等等
Wait!
回来 小家伙
Come back, you Iittle coypu!
爱丽丝 数到三我们就跑
OK, AIice. . . On the count of 3, we run.
一 二
1 , 2...
爱丽丝 等等
Alicc, wait!
等等
Wait!
等等我
Wait for me!
该死
Oh shit!
他们不是走 他们会小跑
They don't walk, thcy trot!
你的主意糟透了 爸爸
Your plan sucks, Dad .
对不起 我尽力了
Sorry, l did my best.
谢谢你
Thank you.
多谢拉夫 我想抛弃你
Thank Raph. I wantcd to abandon you.
谢谢 拉夫
Thanks, Raph.
不客气
No, well , er...
最好别死
Bcst to avoid death.
什么  我们得离开 他们过来了
What?  We gotta go. They'rc coming for us.
抓紧我
Hold on to me.
我把我们传送到安全的地方
I'll tcleporf us to a safe placc.
出发
Let's go
怎么回事  你忘了充电
What's that?  You forgot to chargc it.
这不需要充电 它是太阳能的
It doesn't need charging, it's solarpowcrcd !
好吧 现在是晚上
Wcll , it's nighttime!
我们牺牲掉吉尔伯特吧  不 牺牲你
Let's sacrificc Gilberf.  No, you.
我同意  我不想任何人死
I agree.  l don't want anyone to die.
福克斯 快过来
Pox, over hcre!
韦斯
Wcascl .
快 我们走
Come on, let's go!
跟我们来 臭丧尸们
Pollow us, you zombies!
来吃我们 废物
Come eat us, you losers!
离开这儿
Lct's get out of here!
快走  等等我们
Hurry!  Wait for us!
谁是福克斯
Who's Fox?
我就是
I'm Fox!
都没人在听吗
No one evcr l istcns!
天呐
Holy cow!
马提欧
Mattco.
去向康斯坦斯汇报我们的进展
Go rcporf to Constancc on our progress.
让我送死吗
And get mysclf killcd?
嗨 各位
Hi , guys!
康斯坦斯想听听进度
Constance wants a progress reporf.
理查德 你可以告诉她
Richard, you can tell her
我们遇到了一个小麻烦 发生了爆炸
wc'vc had a minor sctback, an explosion.
不 别说
No, don't.
告诉她我们有线索了
Tcll hcr we have a lead .
但含糊一点 好吗  好的
But be vaguc, OK?
我开着免提 她什么都听到了
You're on speaker. She heard everything .
哦豁
In your facc!
她生气了吗  还开着免提的
Is she pissed off?  You're still on speaker!
告诉她我保证会找到他们
Tcll hcr I promise we'll find them.
各位 动起来 我们需要线索
Guys, movc your asscs! Wc nced clucs.
维克多 把它放下
Victor, put that down!
按照现在的情况 我今晚就会成为队长
The way things are going, I'll bc mission leader tonight!
老  巢
老   巢
让一让
Out thc way!
欢迎来到老巢
Wclcomc to the Lair.
福克斯
Pox!
你好吗
How arc you?
1 2 3
1 , 2, 3!
来吧
Come on.
别动
Kcep still .
谢谢你
Thank you.
不客气
You're welcome.
嘿 别闹了
Hcy, that's enough!
我想再次谢谢你
I wantcd to thank you again.
不客气
No, well , er...
不用 你现在也是团队的一员了
No nced. You're part of the team now.
什么的一员
Parf of what?
团队
The team.
你是我们的一员 如果你愿意的话
You're onc of us. Wcll , if you want to be.
你愿意接受一个21世纪的嬉皮士
You'd acccpt a 21 stccntury hipster?
我们已经有机器人了 所以……
Wc alrcady havc a robot, so...
你有机器人
You have a robot?
什么意思 机器人
What d'you mean, a robot?
不要紧
Ncver mind .
算了吧
Porgct it.
我不想他们来的
I didn't want thcm to come.
他们看起来人畜无害
They scem harmless cnough.
不过那个家伙
That guy though...
他是个真正的威胁
hc's a real menace.
你没看见这根很干净吗
Can't you sce it's clcan?
你是傻子吗
Are you dumb?
我不知道该拿他怎么办
I don't know what to do with him.
你不必杀他
You don't have to kill him.
为了救你 也许得杀
To savc you, maybe.
你无法救所有人
You can't save everyone.
我可以
I can too.
现在是我们救了你
Por now, we saved you.
对
Ycah.
请享用
Enjoy!
嘿 手肘放桌子上
Hcy, elbows on the table!
好多了
That's bettcr.
天天去太累了
It's tiring, going cvcry day.
看起来好好吃 这是什么
This Iooks tasty. What is it?
耗耗
R.O. U .S.
耗耗 好吧
R.O. U .S.? OK.
耗耗是什么
What's R.O.U .S.?
算了 我还是不知道为妙
Porgct it, I'd rathcr not know.
好想法 好好享用吧 吉尔伯特
Good thinking. Enjoy your meal , Gilbcrf.
耗耗就是老鼠 巨型老鼠
R.O. U .S. is rat, giant rat.
真棒
Great!
我说什么了  安静
What did I say?  Ouiet.
亨利
Hcnry?
时间巡警来了
The Time patrol is coming!
时间巡警 不许动
Time patrol ! Precze!
童子军们 就位
Pack, into position!
我们开不开枪
Uo wc shoot or not?
给我个石头
Give mc a rock!
递过去
Pass them on!
我们留在这儿
Wc stay hcrc.
路易丝
Louise?
开火
Pire!
靠
Puck!
现在怎么办 首领
What now, chief?
滚出老巢
Gct out of the Lair!
走开
Gct lost!
我不知道 他们都是孩子
I don't know, thcy're kids!
一起发射
All together now!
对 武装的孩子
Ycah, armcd kids!
去你的时间巡警
Puck the Time patrol !
小兔崽子
Little bastards.
你知道吗
You know what?
尝尝这个 臭小子们
Take that, Lost Boys!
不 维克多
No, Victor!
隐蔽
Take cover!
亨利
Hcnry!
都怪你
This is all your fault!
我知道
I know.
爸爸
Uad !
别 别这样
Uon't. . . Don't do it!
不要 住手
Uon't! Stop!
童子军们
Pack,
放下武器 我们投降
Iay down your arms. Wc surrender.
不
No.
不用……
Uon't be...
我们不是在找你们
Wc'rc not after you.
好吗
All right?
你安全了
You're safe.
不会有事的
It's going to be all right.
我想谢谢你
I wantcd to thank you.
你帮我们抓到了一个臭名昭著的罪犯
You helped us catch a notorious criminal .
试图阻止灾难有什么罪
What's criminal about trying to prevent disasters?
你认为他是英雄
You think hc's a hero?
你搞错了
You're mistaken.
他的每一件“好事” 都会造成间接损害
Every "good decd" of his causcs collateral damage.
那个疯子以为他在拯救世界
The madman thinks hc's saving thc world.
你就打打嘴炮来激励你的机械警察吗
Uo you motivatc your RoboCops with that Iittle spiel?
我可不吃这套
Wcll it won't work on me.
你自称要保护时间
You claim to protect Timc.
但你只是希望一切保持原样
But you want everything to stay as it is.
因为这正合你意
Bccausc it suits you.
因为事情可能会变得更糟
Bccausc things could be worse.
比世界末日更糟吗  一切走到尽头
Than thc cnd of the world?  Evcrything ends.
甚至是世界
Even the world.
不用穿梭时空拯救地球
No nced to timc travel to savc the planct.
我会阻止爸爸修建核电站  你不会的
L'll stop Dad building the plant.  You will not.
为什么 你是要……
Why? Are you going...
折磨你
To torfurc you?
我有更能让你折服的方法
I have more persuasivc mcans.
让你直面你的矛盾
To confront you with your contradictions.
你是我吗
Are you mc?
老年的
Old?
33岁不算老
33 isn't old.
确实 反正这不可能
It is. lt's impossiblc anyway.
你经历了这么多
After all you've becn through,
还不相信我是未来的你
you don't bcl icvc I'm thc futurc you?
我最爱的电影是什么
What are my favoritc movies?
《爱在》系列四部曲
The Beforc Saga.
在你的时代只有三部曲 所以忘了最后一部吧
It was a trilogy in your day, so forget the last onc.
你为何在这儿
Why arc you here?
康斯坦斯带我来的
Constance brought mc.
她想让我以“你”的身份告诉你我的经验
To tcll you what l heard when I was in your place.
我们不偷爸爸的电脑
Wc'rc not stealing Dad's computcr.
为什么
Why?
因为这是错的
Bccausc it's wrong.
就这些吗
Is that it?
I'm not going to spoil your Iifc by rcvcaling minc.
我不会透露我的生活来破坏你的生活
我想你一定过得很开心
I bet you had a wild timc!
没错
That's right.
我去结识伙伴 去旅游
I've mct peoplc, l've travcled .
我的人生很精彩
I have a grcat Iife.
多亏了爸爸
And all thanks to Dad.
我可以过我自己的人生  不 你不能
I can Iivc my own Iife.  No, you can't.
我发誓我不想这么说  但你不能
I hate to say so, I swear, but you can't.
没有爸爸 我们只能在打工路上苦逼挣扎
Wc'd bc struggling without Dad , doing shitty jobs.
因为说实话
Bccausc to be honest,
除了怨天尤人
aparf from moaning about the world...
我们非常没用
Wc'rc pretty useless.
没错
That's right.
还有其他事
Therc's somcthing elsc.
他会生病
Hc's going to get sick.
怎么了  你知道怎么了
What's wrong?  You know what's wrong.
妈妈死后他就一直酗酒
Hc's bcen drinking since Mom dicd .
他会需要你
Hc's going to necd you.
直到最后一刻
Until the vcry end .
我不信你
I don't bclievc you.
你在胡说八道
You're talking crap.
他最后会变得成熟
Hc'Il mellow towards the end .
你可以和他交流
You'll be able to talk.
我现在就可以和他交流
I can talk to him now.
我会叫他放弃
I'll tcll him to quit.
已经太迟了
It's already too late.
已经……
It's already...
告诉他你爱他
Tcll him you Iovc him.
可能听起来很蠢
It might sound dumb,
但很重要
but it's imporfant.
相信我
Bcl icvc mc.
抱歉让你失望了
Sorry to disappoint you.
我没这么说过
I didn't say you did .
但我是站在你的角度考虑的
But I thought that in your placc.
现在干嘛
What now?
你去睡觉
You're going to bed.
爱丽丝呢
And AIice?
她会知道该做什么
She'll know what to do.
谢谢你的配合
Thank you for your cooperation.
抱歉我有点欣喜若狂
Sorry to look so ovcrjoycd.
乐意效劳 康斯坦斯
Glad to bc of service, Constancc.
福克斯
Pox...
你不该如此傲慢
your arrogance is inappropriate.
你残害了生命  也救了很多生命
You've destroycd lives.  And savcd many.
我不信
I doubt it.
你不记得而已
But you don't remember.
你知道为什么吗
Uo you know why?
当我们完成一个任务
When wc accomplish a mission
骗过你时 时间会重新开始
and outfox you, Timc starts over again.
所以你们记不得
So you can't rcmcmbcr.
你气不气
Infuriating, isn't it?
那你记得吗
Uo you remember?
只有改变时间的人才能记得所改之事
Only thosc who alter Timc rcmembcr thc othcr real itics.
这是规则
That's thc rulc.
频繁吗
Is it frequcnt?
你根本不知道
You have no idca!
他在说谎
Hc's Iying .
他一直满口谎言
Hc always does.
为了吓唬你
To unscttle you.
而且起效了  对我无效
And it works.  Not on me.
你的犯罪活动到此结束
This is the end of your criminal activities.
你完了 福克斯
You're finished , Pox.
今天是个大日子
Today's the big day!
你要和阿克索签协议
You're signing the deal with Axomako.
对 他们在等我们
Ycs. They'rc expccting us.
压力山大
The prcssurc!
针对你的罪行
Por your crimes,
我要判你长期洞刑
I am scntcncing you to a Iong stay in the Hole.
什么洞
What's thc Holc?
一个不存在时间的监狱
A prison whcre Time does not cxist.
我希望你和爱丽丝和好了
I hope you madc up with AIice.
差不多吧  她是个好姑娘
More or Icss.  Shc's a great girl .
我是说真的
I mean that respcctfully.
请你看路
Eyes on the road, please.
反对父亲需要莫大的勇气
It takcs guts to oppose your dad.
法比奥  嗯
Pabio.  Yes?
你话太多了  好的 先生
You talk too much.  Yes, sir.
但你说的对
But you'rc right.
需要勇气
It takcs guts.
调头
Turn around.
是吗
What?
我们回家
Wc'rc going home.
有点不对劲
Something's amiss.
时间更改中
你不是有个会议吗
Uon't you have a mecting?
我宁愿在这儿陪你
I'd rather be here with you.
核电站怎么办
What about the plant?
她不会同意的
She wouldn't havc approvcd.
我希望你认识她
I wish you'd known her.
医生为什么不救妈妈
Why didn't the doctor save Mom?
他想救你们两个
Hc wanted to savc you both.
但我还有你
But I havc you.
你知道
You know...
我依然喜欢《小乌龟富兰克林》
I still Iikc Pranklin thc Turflc.
我就知道
I kncw it!
怎么回事
What's going on?
我不明白
I don't gct it.
出现了一个转变
A change is underway?
是内部转变
It's an intcrnal change.
是吉尔伯特自己 不是我们
It's Gilbcrf, not us.
你无法插手
You can't interfcre.
我想怎样就怎样
I can do whatever I Iike.
马提欧 路易丝 去找吉尔伯特
Mattco, Louise, find Gilberf.
不 康斯坦斯  确保他去参加会议
Don't, Constance!  Make sure he goes to his mecting.
要是他不肯呢
If hc refuscs?
用他女儿性命威胁他
Threatcn to kill his daughter.
什么
What?
她没有任何用处 我研究过她的生活
She serves no purpose. I studied hcr life.
她毫无野心
She lacks ambition.
她改变不了时间
She cannot altcr Time.
等等 我们差点杀死一群孩子
Hang on, we almost killed somc kids!
你在抗命吗
You refusc?
很好 维克多 你做队长
Vcry wcll . Victor, you're mission Icader.
我说什么来着
What did I tell you?
和马提欧一起去
Go with Matteo.
除非他反对
Unless he objects?
不会 我们走吧
No. Let's go.
摩尔 我让你把绿线焊接到红线上
Mole, I askcd you to solder the grcen wire to the red wirc.
然后将绿线连到控制器上
Then conncct the grcen wirc to the console.
对我的膝盖骨温柔点
Gcntly with my kneecap.
摩尔 绿线接到红线上
Mole, the green wirc to thc rcd wire!
谢谢 亲爱的 这刚好是我不想要的
Thank you, swectie! It's just what I didn't want.
博士  等一下
Doctor?  Onc second.
我说的是小钳子 斯康克
I said thc small pliers, Skunk.
摩尔 你到底能不能看见
Mole, it's the. . . Can you sce or not?
博士
Uoctor!
干嘛
What?
我们有麻烦了
Wc havc a problem.
待在这儿
Stay therc.
时间巡警 混蛋
Time patrol , motherfucker!
什么情况
What is this?
跟马提欧走 这个女孩跟我待着
Go with Matteo. The girl stays with mc.
不要轻举妄动
Just hold on!
放开我
Lct go of mc!
闭嘴
Shut it!
老大说她和她的人生无药可救
The boss says shc's hopeless and her Iifc is too.
所以就算她死了
So if she dies...
也不会有人在意
no one will give a shit.
放开我
Lct go of mc!
吉尔伯特 按要求做 事情自然会解决
Gilbcrf, do what was askcd of you and things'll work out.
我知道你尽力了 爸爸
I know you tricd, Dad.
这才是最重要的
That's all that matters.
对不起
I'm sorry.
走吧
Lct's go.
我不知道我笑什么
I don't know why l'm laughing!
别动
Uon't movc.
你走火入魔了 康斯坦斯
You've lost, Constancc.
我们保护时间进程 如果我们失败 大家都会完蛋
Wc protect the course of Time. If wc losc, evcryonc loscs.
路易丝 把犯人带去洞里
Louise, takc the prisoners to the Hole.
理查德
Richard...
和他们一起去 监督他们
go with them and supervise.
明白
Understood .
法比奥 去办公室
Pabio, thc officc.
他是谁  不要多问
Who's hc?  Don't ask qucstions!
好的
Right...
程序是这样的 你爬进洞去
The procedure is this: you climb into the Hole
你不会有任何感觉
and you won't fecl a thing.
我是这么听说的
Or so I'vc heard.
理查德
Richard...
这下面有些奇怪的东西
therc's somcthing wcird down thcre.
有什么
What?
你
You!
如果你们成功了 没有人会记得 对吗
If you succced, no one will remember that, right?
除了你 其他巡警都不会
No one in the patrol but you.
因为帮了我们 你被卷入了时间更改
By hclping us, you're involved in thc timc change.
你不记得了 因为我们是敌人
You don't rcmembcr bccausc wc werc cnemics
不过我们见过好几次了
but we've mct several times.
好吧
Wcll ...
很高兴再次见到你们
nice to mcet you, again.
你们需要什么
OK, what do you guys need?
如果康斯坦斯认为我在后面反抗过 那就太好了
It'd bc great if Constance thinks I put up a fight back thcrc.
当然 一个会空手道的真英雄
Sure. A rcal hcro who did karatc!
真的吗  假的
Seriously?  No.
有碰到谁吗  没有 拿到装备了吗
Run into anyonc?  No. Got the gear?
我们在一个罪犯身上发现了这个
Wc found this on a criminal
从你手上拿走了这个
and took this from you.
知道怎么用吗  当然
Know how to usc it?  Sure.
我不只是打游戏 我有时也会观察
I don't just play vidco games, I observe sometimes.
很高兴听你这么说
Glad to hcar it.
计划是这样
Hcre's thc plan.
拉夫去救爱丽丝 告诉他爸爸她已经安全
Raph, savc Al ice and tell her dad shc's safc.
我去对付马提欧 路易丝呢
I'll dcal with Mattco. Louise?
我去对付康斯坦斯
I'll take care of Constancc.
你能行吗 维克多虽然蠢 不过很危险
Will you be OK? Victor's dumb but dangerous.
没问题 我会搞偷袭 他不会看到我……
Sure, I'Il sneak up on him. Hc won't sec mc...
过来的
...coming!
卧槽
Oh fuck!
你到了吗  快了
Arc you therc yet?  AImost.
一切尽在掌握中
Everything's undcr control .
犯人已经处置完毕
Wc dcalt with thc prisoncrs.
理查德呢
Wherc's Richard?
什么声音
What was that?
我靠
Oh fuck!
犯人逃跑了
The prisoners have cscapcd!
拜拜
Byebyc.
拉夫
Raph?
Raph!
不许动
Uon't movc.
别动了
Stop moving!
有本事
Catch...
就来
mc...
抓我呀
if you can!
抓到你了
Gotcha!
他没事吧  呆在车上
Is hc OK?  Stay in the car.
你个混……
You bas...
这……
But...
他去哪儿了 喵
Wherc's hc gonc?
蛋
...tard!
马提欧 祝你好运
Mattco, good Iuck!
钳子 钳子 钳子
Pliers, plicrs, pl icrs!
怎么样了
Wherc are you at?
我通常有更多的时间来制造时空穿梭机
I usually have more time to build timetravel machines!
我能帮什么忙  给我找只眼睛 胳膊 腿
How can I help?  Pind me an eye, arms, legs!
接触器
Contactor!
博士 我们得赶紧做出来
Uoc, wc havc to get them out.
我已经尽力了
I'm doing my bcst!
我靠
Oh shit!
不许动
Preeze!
再见
So Iong!
我们从没好好谈过
Wc'vc nevcr had a good chat.
等等
Hang on.
好 知道你可以憋住气 现在出来
OK, so you can hold your breath, now get out!
我就知道
I kncw it!
投降吧
Surrcnder.
这是你自找的
You asked for this!
停下 他已经晕过去了
Stop! He's unconscious.
谢谢 爱丽丝
Thanks, Alice.
不客气
No, well , er...
我都没做太多 我没有这样的计划
I didn't do much. I didn't have a plan as such.
我遇到了麻烦
I was in thc shit!
对
Right.
您得马上给你爸打电话
You have to call your dad , now!
太迟了
It's too late.
我们抓到你朋友了
Wc'vc got your friend.
快点 他们在等着
Hurry up, they'rc waiting!
对不起
I'm sorry.
我失败了
I've failcd.
孩子们怎么办
What about the childrcn?
你能帮帮他们吗
Can you hclp them?
我不会这么做的
I won't do it.
什么
What?
牺牲老爸拯救世界
Sacrifice Uad to save thc world.
这是不对的
It isn't right.
有计划了吗
Got a plan?
有
Ycs.
但你不会喜欢的
But you won't like it.
继续
Go on.
我想就是这样了 拉布斯
I gucss this is it, Labuse.
再见 孩子
So Iong, sonny.
人们可以教你很多东西
Pcople can teach you so much.
你却什么都没教我
You've taught me nothing.
除了友情
Except friendship.
我过得很开心
And I've had so much fun.
这很棒 拉布斯 保持住
It's bcen great, Labuse. Uon't changc.
别再杀戮了
Just stop killing.
走吧 托马斯
Come on, Thomas.
西蒙博士 拉布斯
Ur. Simon, Labusc,
再见
so Iong!
对不起
I'm sorry.
我不想威胁那个女孩 她只是无害的平民
I didn't want to threaten the girl . She's a harmless civilian.
不要小看她
Uon't undcrcstimate hcr.
什么鬼
What the. . .?
开始吧
Hcre wc go!
爱丽丝
Alicc?
我不明白
I don't undcrstand .
你听到了
You heard mc.
保大人
Save the mother,
不保小孩
not thc daughtcr.
我能两个都保
I can savc both.
不
No.
你不能
You can't.
保母亲
The mother.
不保孩子
Not thc daughtcr.
快照做
Uo as she says.
爱丽丝在抹除自己的存在
Alicc is crasing hersclf from Time.
我们赢了
Wc'vc won.
你对此不会有任何记忆
You won't rcmembcr any of this.
你好
Hcllo.
你是谁
Who arc you?
谁也不是
Nobody.
不 这不可能
No! This can't bc happening!
我不想忘记她
I don't want to forget hcr!
她叫爱丽丝
Hcr name's Al ice.
她叫……
Hcr name's...
爱丽丝是谁
Who's Al ice?
她是……
She's...
这是你姐姐的名字
Alicc was your sistcr's name.
不过她是死胎
But shc was stillborn.
真可悲
That's sad .
现在有你在 这才是最重要的
You're here now. That's what counts.
爸爸表情为何这么奇怪
Why's Dad pulling a wcird facc?
我应该签署什么东西的
I was supposed to sign somcthing.
我记不得是什么了
I don't rcmcmbcr what.
老年痴呆症来咯
Alzhcimer's strikes!
你昨天签了这个协议 看
You signed the dcal ycstcrday, look.
你现在放假了
You're on vacation now.
阿利伯特启动可再生能源试验项目
我想起来了 太棒了
I remember now. Pantastic!
你太棒了
You're wondcrful .
你真是美极了
You're so bcautiful .
我爱你
I love you.
我也爱你 你没事吧
Mc too. Are you OK?
我喜欢你的发型
I love your hair that way.
你闻着好香 亲爱的
You smcll good, honcy.
你没事吧 恢复正常了吗
You OK? Back to normal?
是的
Ycs.
每次都会有点痛  那是当然
It's always a bit painful .  Only natural .
你的大脑在重新规划现实的层次
Your brain is rearranging the layers of real ity.
最后脑子会坏掉
It'Il cnd up as mush.
大家怎么样 那片云呢
How is evcryonc? And thc cloud?
仿佛从未存在过
As if it never existed.
孩子们呢  一如既往的邋遢
And the kids?  As grubby as ever!
你输了
You lost!
太好了
Good.
我们成功了
Wc did it.
有个巡警帮过我们一次
A patrol member helped us for once.
不同于她的伙伴 我们的盟友记得一切
Unl ike her buddics, our ally remembers cvcrything.
我们拉拢了一个内部人员
Wc'vc turned an agent.
路易丝
Louise.
康斯坦斯
Constance.
如果我们能拉拢一个
And if we can turn onc...
机会便是无穷无尽的
the opporfunities are endlcss.
时空穿梭没有规则 那我们可以随心所欲
Time travcl has no rules? Wc can do whatcvcr we l ike.
不 你没明白吗
No. You don't get it, eh?
爱丽丝创造了一个前所未有的时间悖论
Alicc creatcd a totally unprcccdentcd time paradox.
这很危险 可能会造成出乎意料的后果
It was risky and could havc had dramatic consequences.
好吧  懂了吗
OK.  Got that?
没有
No.
重要的是她成功了
What mattcrs is that she succceded.
还有她一直在等她的酒
And shc's bcen waiting for her drink!
天生爱抱怨
A born complainer!
十五分钟或一个世纪 时间总是相对的
Piftcen minutes or a century, time's always relativc.
对吧  不对 拉夫
Right?  Nope, Raph.
谢谢让我加入这个团队
Thanks for having mc on thc tcam.
不过我为什么还在这儿
Why am l still hcre though?
你终止了你的出生
You canceled your birfh.
然而如果你死了就无法在那个现实中
Uying , however, would havc undonc your act
完成你的行为
in that vcrsion of real ity.
懂了吗
Got that?
你的存在伴随着不存在
You cxist without having existed.
你是现实的一个例外
You're onc of real ity's driftcrs.
反正我觉得我存在
I fecl l cxist though.
我们先喝几杯再讨论
Wc'Il discuss that after a few pints.
我们喝
Lct's drink!
世界末日后的
第一家酒吧
来自未来的访客
纪 念  普 朗 西 斯·波 斯 弗 拉 格
开拍！
Action!
不，别扔那个罐子！
No! Do not throw that can!